One of the frequently asked questions and exercises in university and interviews is how to detect a
loop in the injured list.
Not obligatory that the last node in the linked list will refer indifference to that.
Now it may be a reference to another No.
OK.
Exactly like this shape.
So we have five nodes, 100, 200, 300, 400 and 500, and the last node this 500 is referencing to
200 and this is the cycle.
This is the loop that we are going to check if this link list is telling us and referencing two in loop
or not.
OK.
The algorithm tells us to make two pointers, fast and slow and.
They are at the position had.
So the farce that we have seen in the previous videos.
It removes two by two.
OK.
Two nuts.
While the slow moves by one so and has loop, this is that this is the and the method that we are going
to work with to detect if this has a loop or not.
So the struck don't slow and slow, slow and fast equal to had they are at the head, while slow does
not equal to null and fast does not equal to none.
And Fast Pointer next does not equal to null makes law next and fast.
Next.
OK, Fast will move two by two two knots, while slow will move by one if slow.
Equal.
Equal to first, then return one.
OK, this is how they meet here.
Slow and fast and it returns one that detects that there is a loop.
So this is the algorithm behind their detection of a loop inside linked list.
So we create two pointers and they move one two by two and the other by one.
And if they meet at specific condition, we're using the while loop, then it will return one if it
is there, if there is a loop, if not, it will not return.